RESUME

SARAH K. RUSSELL

PROFILE

I'm Sarah K. Russell: a Frontend Website Developer of over 16 years. I would love to join a company that shares my passion for website development. My degree in graphic design has given me a great resource and an eye for content layout that I'm able to apply to my website projects. I'm always excited to jump into a challenging new project or learn new skills. I'm currently expanding my knowledge of JavaScript, jQuery, CSS Grid and Flexbox.

CONTACT

CONIFER, CO

Email: sarah@skrdesign.com

Web: www.skrdesign.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarahrussell-ar33049/

EXPERTISE

- Frontend Web
 Development
- HTML5
- CSS₃ / Sass / Less
- Mobile First
- Responsive
- Git / GitHub / GitLab
- Bootstrap 4
- Foundation 6
- CMS systems
- Node
- Grunt
- Gulp
- Command line
- WCAG AA ADA
 Compliance standards
- Mac & Windows Systems
- Communication
- Work in a team and individually
- Delivering on time
- Learn quickly

EXPERIENCE

Advanced Web Builder

PROFITSTARS (A JACK HENRY & ASSOCIATES COMPANY)

REMOTE - CONIFER, CO / TEAM - NASHVILLE, TN

2014 - 2019

Hired after a six month contract. Worked in Nashville office until moving to Conifer in July of 2017.

Work independently building responsive websites for banking and financial institutions based on the designer provided mockups. Sites are built using Bootstrap, HTML5, Sass, JavaScript, jQuery, Git, Node, Gulp, and Grunt. Built to meet WCAG AA ADA standards and are added to a Content Management System within project timelines.

Web Builder Process Documentation team member. Process is updated constantly to reflect the constant industry changes and our documentation must reflect that for other builders to reference.

Frontend Website Developer / Owner

SKR DESIGN LLC / CONIFER, CO

2003 - Present

Frontend website development company specializing in designing and building custom web sites with a focus on reflecting the client's identity online within budget and on time. Handle all aspects of the project from design concept, branding, coding, launching and maintaining the site. Focus on building sites that reflect the client in the best way while providing a positive, easy to navigate experience for the user. For clients who want to update their own content, the site is added to a CMS.

SKR Design currently has four active clients; most have been with the company for over 9 years, while the newest client is under two years old. Clients are listed on the portfolio website, www.skrdesign.com.

Indie Rock Band Social Media Manager & Webmaster

SARAH K. RUSSELL / NASHVILLE, TN / CONIFER, CO 2009 - Present

Design, build and maintain band websites for Black Market Research (current) and Tyrone Carreker (2012-2014). Regularly design and send out email newsletters to fans. Represent the band on social media and at shows in Nashville. Ran three successful Kickstarter campaigns that funded recording sessions and production of three band albums.

SARAH K. RUSSELL

PAGE TWO

SKILLS

- Basic JavaScript / jQuery
- SEO
- Social Media management
- Email Design
- Sublime / Atom
- Visual Studio
- Illustrator
- Photoshop
- Fireworks
- Word

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Design – Visual Communications Design UNIVERSITY OF ALBERTA Edmonton, Alberta, Canada

INTERESTS

- Fly Fishing
- World Traveling
- Books
- Knitting
- Skiing
- Kayaking
- Hiking
- Camping
- Backpacking
- Photography
- Board Games

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Content Developer

ACXIOM / NASHVILLE, TN

2009 - 2014

Promoted from Content Specialist.

HTML specialist, responsible for; integrating, testing and approving high quality business to-customer emails. Create emails that render responsively across browsers and mobile devices. Provide suggestions and recommendations directly to the client. Content lead, Sam's Club and American Cancer Society.

Group member in; Platform Quality Assurance Group, Associate Satisfaction Survey Results Committee, and Acxiom's Nashville Office Events Committee.

PORTFOLIO SITE

SKR Design LLC

www.skrdesign.com

This past January, the portfolio site was rebuilt to reflect the wonderful changes in our industry toward Flexbox and CSS Grid layouts. The homepage is a Flexbox layout, while the interior page layout was more suited to CSS Grid. The design concept came from a love of books. Books and websites are very much the same – a medium for information or telling a story. The mobile first, responsive site was built with a Foundation 6 base, Yarn, Sass, Flexbox and CSS Grid.

REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST